Philip Carlsson

Problem solver, thorough, and eager to learn

Contact

Telephone number: 0046 73 51 57 567 E-mail: philipcarlsson@hotmail.com LinkedIn Profile

GitHub



Professional Profile

Web Development knowledge

HTML,

CSS, Sass, TailwindCSS JavaScript, TypeScript React, NextJS, React Testing Library, Jest, Vitest,

JSON, TanStack Query, React

Hook Form, Yup NodeJS, Express,

PHP,

WordPress,

WooCommerce,

MySQL, MongoDB, NoSQL,

Docker,

GitHub,

Agile Methodologies, Jira,

Who am I?

Strategic, organised and a quick learner who thrive in a fast-paced environment. An up-and-coming web developer with various additional skills.

What motivates me?

I am motivated by solving problems and making a difference. Learning new programming languages, concepts, and more effective code stimulates me greatly.

Languages

Swedish: Mother tongue

English: Fluent

French: High school level, six years

Arabic: Read and write

References

Available upon request.

Education

Medieinstitutet, Stockholm, Web Development E-Commerce 2021 – 2023

Calle Flygare Theatre School, Stockholm 2016 – 2018 Uppsala University, Bachelor's degree in economics 2012 – 2015

Adelphi University, New York, USA, economics 2011 – 2012 **Dubai American Academy,** United Arab Emirates, International Baccalaureate Program 2009 – 2011

Kungsholmens Gymnasium, Stockholm, Pre-International Baccalaureate Program 2008 – 2009

Cairo American College, Egypt, Middle & High School 2006 – 2008

Work experience

Frontend intern at Stryda (Ex G-Loot), Stockholm Oct 2022 – Present

My first project involved migrating Stryda's internally built admin system from JavaScript to **Typescript**, including replacing depreciated dependencies, refactoring, and building new functionality - such as **API CRUD operations** to get or change user data.

My second project was to create a back-office for Stryda's flagship product. Before the Business Intelligence team manually worked in Swagger with JSON data as configuration. Now the BI team have automized weekly configuration work, which has **reduced manual labour from hours to minutes**, and potential human errors. The project also allows outside teams to work with the product.

Now we are working on another feature with the same goal as above: simplifying ways of working, improving user experience.

During my time at Stryda I have been responsible to **lead daily stand-ups**, **backlog refinements**, **sprint retros** and create new tickets for the team.

Board Member at FC Krukan, Stockholm

March 2022 - Present

Built a RSVP'ing app for the team's matches. Please check it out! Github repo

Note-taking Support at Medieinstitutet, Stockholm

Sept 2021 – Present

Collection & Trading at Ikano Bank AB, Stockholm

Feb 2020 - Sept 2022

My primary responsibility in this role is to minimize financial loss and mitigate risks within Ikano Bank's B2B leasing segment for clients that are insolvent, in bankruptcy or under reconstruction.

I negotiate with clients, vendors, subcontractors, and legal advisers. I analyse and perform research, as a basis for the negotiation on how to reach the best arrangement for the parties involved.

Sales Manager at Coop Sverige AB, Stockholm

May 2019 – Jan 2020

Promoted to second in line behind the store manager. My areas of responsibilities included controlling purchase orders, analysing sales performance, supplier relations, reviewing invoices, cash out, delegating tasks, and creating the work schedule for all employees.

Freelance Actor, Sweden

2018 - 2019

Not only have I acted, but also directed, been part of creative groups, written and edited scripts. Most notably I have a role in Richard Holm's **TV-series Heder**, which aired during the fall of 2019. I have acted in plays as well as taken additional responsibilities to aid other actors and setting the stage.

Sales Assistant at Coop Sverige AB, Stockholm

Oct 2017 - May 2019

Part time job during my studies and freelancing.

Leasing Administrator at Upplands Motor AB, Stockholm

Jun 2015 - Oct 2017

Responsible for the administration of leasing deals, payment of general agent cars, current record of accounting, and auditing invoices. Once I started my education at Calle Flygare Theatre School, Upplands Motor offered me to work part time from home and I also spent an additional summer working in their office.

Chef at Boule & Berså, Stockholm

Summertime 2012 - 2014

I include this on my CV because of the stress levels I endured and overcame during my three summers in a tiny kitchen. Started as a chef's assistant but quickly rose and obtained more responsibilities.

Editor of Vinvalls Website, Stockholm

2012

My mission was to edit their website, in English, ahead of their conference of wind power and climate issues.